<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on Nick Cobb</title>
    <link>https://cobbservations.com/categories/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on Nick Cobb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 23:22:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cobbservations.com/categories/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://cobbservations.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 23:22:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cobbservations.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Nick is currently a Senior Systems Engineer on the Developer Productivity team at Uber Advanced Technologies. At Uber ATG, his main focus is building reliable, immutable infrastructure and improving the developer experience for self-driving developers.
In years previous, Nick supported mobile continuous integration infrastructure for Uber&amp;rsquo;s massive mobile engineering organization. In addition, Nick also provided full support for Uber&amp;rsquo;s global core business units in areas such as endpoint management, telecommunications strategy, network topologies, and scalability planning and design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is this thing on?</title>
      <link>https://cobbservations.com/blog/is-this-thing-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 23:22:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cobbservations.com/blog/is-this-thing-on/</guid>
      <description>Wat This is the initial post in a series of steps I am taking to move Cobbservations to a site powered by Hugo. I stumbled across hugo recently while working with the maintainers of the micromdm project. The beautiful site hosting the documentation is build with hugo, and given the looks, I just had to try it.
Somewhat separately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Markdown for quite a while and have finally gotten around to enjoying it more than standard wordpress-style content for blogging.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>