<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fixed on Nick Cobb</title>
    <link>https://loyaltyarm.github.io/fixed/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fixed on Nick Cobb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 23:22:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://loyaltyarm.github.io/fixed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://loyaltyarm.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 23:22:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loyaltyarm.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently a Senior Systems Engineer on the Developer Productivity team at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uberatc.com&#34;&gt;Uber Advanced Technologies&lt;/a&gt;. At Uber ATG, my main focus is building reliable, (sometimes) immutable infrastructure or services to improve the developer experience for self-driving engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous years at Uber, I built, managed, and supported mobile continuous integration infrastructure for our massive mobile engineering organization. In addition, I also provided full support for Uber&amp;rsquo;s global core business operations in areas such as endpoint management, telecommunications strategy, network topologies, and scalability planning and design. If you want to know more about what I did before Uber, reach out to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to regularly &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/loyaltyarm/speaking&#34;&gt;speak at conferences&lt;/a&gt; and am a fan of baseball and bodybuilding. I also travel regularly and enjoy trying new restaurants with friends and family. My current challenges include learning how to be a (new) uncle and discovering ways to advance his technology learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>