<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apple on Nick Cobb</title>
    <link>https://loyaltyarm.github.io/tags/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apple on Nick Cobb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 02:01:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://loyaltyarm.github.io/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement: iOS MDM should allow display timeout management without passcode</title>
      <link>https://loyaltyarm.github.io/blog/enhancement-ios-mdm-should-allow-display-timeout-management-without-passcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 02:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loyaltyarm.github.io/blog/enhancement-ios-mdm-should-allow-display-timeout-management-without-passcode/</guid>
      <description>Hey all!
I&amp;rsquo;ve just opened rdar://30582319 in response to some testing I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing to attempt to manage the auto-lock settings on various iOS devices used as kiosks. In our case, we want to be able to set the display timeout to &amp;lsquo;15 minutes&amp;rsquo; or ideally &amp;lsquo;Never&amp;rsquo;, but not require the device to have a passcode enabled.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been testing this with a custom config profile, of which I&amp;rsquo;ve created a gist here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homebrew on Sierra now requires the latest Xcode</title>
      <link>https://loyaltyarm.github.io/blog/homebrew-on-sierra-now-requires-the-latest-xcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 11:15:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loyaltyarm.github.io/blog/homebrew-on-sierra-now-requires-the-latest-xcode/</guid>
      <description>While fumbling my way through a bootstrapping workflow for macOS Sierra, I found that recent updates to Homebrew now require the latest version of Xcode when the machine in question is running macOS Sierra.
It looks like the check boils down to a scenario when the relevant machine is running macOS Sierra AND does NOT have the CI attribute.
If the CI attribute is specified, then the Homebrew check will proceed and allow a different version of Xcode to be installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centering GMSMapView on User&#39;s Current Location - Google Maps SDK for iOS</title>
      <link>https://loyaltyarm.github.io/blog/centering-gmsmapview-on-users-current-location---google-maps-sdk-for-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 01:27:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://loyaltyarm.github.io/blog/centering-gmsmapview-on-users-current-location---google-maps-sdk-for-ios/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on a personal project that involves the use of the Google Maps SDK for iOS. As I am still picking up various tidbits and skills related to iOS development, I did a bit of learning first in order to get started. Code School recently opened up a free channel for learning about using Google Maps SDK for iOS, and that has been pretty helpful. According to the Google Maps SDK documentation, there are various ways to create a mapView and assign its camera position, or force a camera update.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>